Guide to the Knight Biggerstaff papers, 1923-2000,
Biggerstaff, Knight papers, 1923-2000
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Knight Biggerstaff papers, 1923-2000, 1944-1961 (bulk).
14-17-629
Knight Biggerstaff, 1906-
12.7 cubic ft.
Correspondence, memoranda, notes.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes materials relating to Knight Biggerstaff's career as a scholar of Chinese history, including extensive records of travel in the Far East, and to his term as chair of the History Department at Cornell University.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of Chinese History, 1927-1978; Chairman, Department of Far Eastern Studies, Cornell University, 1946-1956; Chairman, History Department, Cornell University, 1956-1965.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes administrative correspondence of both departments and correspondence, memoranda, minutes, reports, notes, and other items concerning his participation in the American Council of Learned Societies and its Committee on Far Eastern Studies, American Historical Association, Association for Asian Studies, and Institute of Pacific Relations, of which he was a trustee of the American branch; some of the IPR records relate to the McCarran Subcommittee investigation of that organization. Professor Biggerstaff's handwritten notes (1927-1933) from Harvard University classes and lecture notes for his own Cornell classes and for the Army Special Training Program at Cornell (1944), all relating to the Far East. Also, letters to Biggerstaff and drafts of some of Biggerstaff's outgoing correspondence with fellow China scholars, students and personal friends; letters of recommendation for former students and colleagues; documentation of Biggerstaff's travel and study abroad (China and Europe); reviews of colleagues' books for historical publications; and material describing his security hearings in 1954 including Biggerstaff's statement in defense of his own loyalty as well as statements for many colleagues (c.1954). Frequent correspondents include China scholars such as: George H. Blakeslee, O. Edmund Clubb, John K. Fairbank, George McTuran Kahin, and Ssu-yü Teng.
Also, letters, 1961-1991, from Dr. Biggerstaff to Dr. Arun K. Dasgupta, a graduate student of his who returned to Calcutta, India and also taught in Jakarta, Indonesia. Includes personal, family, and professional news; also, Biggerstaff's letters from China (1945-49) and Camilla Biggerstaff's letters from China (1923-31).
These papers include correspondence to the Biggerstaff and drafts of some of Biggerstaff's outgoing correspondence with fellow China scholars, students, and personal friends; letters of recommendation for former students and colleagues; documentation of Biggerstaff's travel and study abroad (china and Europe); reviews of colleagues' books for historical publications; and material describing his security hearings in 1954 including Biggerstaff's statement in defense of correspondents include China scholars such as: George H. Blakeslee, O. Edmund Clubb, John K. Fairbank, George McT. Kahin, and Ssu-yu Teng.
Material is arranged alphabetically within 2 or 3 year periods, as Professor Biggerstaff left the papers. These periods often correspond roughly to inclusive dates. Series indicate original groupings of material by box. Althouhg the material remains in the same overall order as Professor Biggerstaff arranged it, some groups of material were consolidated or divided into different folders to facilitate storage. The alphabetical order is not always apparent but has been maintained wherever possible.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Biggerstaff, Knight, 1906-; Biggerstaff, Camilla.; Blakeslee, George Hubbard, 1871-1954.; Clubb, O. Edmund (Oliver Edmund), 1901-; Dasgupta, Arun Kumar, 1925-; Fairbank, John King, 1907-; Kahin, George McTurnan.; Teng, Ssu-yü, 1906-; American Council of Learned Societies. Committee on Far Eastern Studies.; American Historical Association.; Association for Asian Studies.; Cornell University. Dept. of History.; Cornell University. Army Special Training Program.; Cornell University. Dept. of Far Eastern Studies.; Harvard University.; Institute of Pacific Relations.; United States. Congress. House. Committee on Un-American Activities.
Places:
China--Description and travel.; China--Study and teaching.; United States--History--1945-1953.; United States--History--1953-1961.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. History Department files
Boxes 1-3
Series II. 1928-1931, First three years in China (living in Peking), first year at the North China Union Language School learning Chinese, next two years at Yenching University (on a Harvard-Yenching Institute fellowship) pursuing graduate studies in Chinese history; travel in other parts of China, briefly in Korea
Box 4
Series III. 1931-1934, Graduate study at Harvard, completing Ph.D.
Boxes 4-5
Series IV. 1934-1936, Post-doctoral study in Peking on Social Science Research Council fellowship; published An Annotated Bibliography of Selected Chinese Reference Works with S.Y. Teng
Box 5
Series V. 1936-1938, Instructor in Chinese history and language at the University of Washington
Boxes 5-6
Series VI. 1938-1940, First two years at Cornell as Assistant Professor of Chinese History
Boxes 6-7
Series VII. 1940-1942, At Cornell, including 1942 Summer Workshop on Far East, British Commonwealth and Latin America and 1941 American Council of Learned Societies, Chinese and Japanese Language Courses
Boxes 7-8
Series VIII. 1938-1940, Records as Secretary of Committee on Chinese Studies of the American Council of Learned Societies
Boxes 8-9
Series IX. 1940-1941, Records as Secretary of Committee on Chinese Studies of the American Council of Learned Societies
Boxes 9-10
Series X. 1942-1944, War Years at Cornell, including material of Committee on Asiatic Studies of ACLS. All material on the Chinese Army Specialized Training Program Biggerstaff directed is filed with other ASTP records in University Archives
Boxes 10-11
Series XI. 1944-1946, Six months in Division of Territorial Studies, U.S. Dept. of State and one year as Chinese Secretary of U.S. Embassy Chungking
Box 11
Series XII. 1946-1947, From June 1946, return to Cornell; most correspondence as Chairman of Department of Chinese (later, Far Eastern and still later, Asian) Studies is in that department's files
Boxes 11-12
Series XIII. 1947-1949, Includes material regarding an American Historical Association Program Committee, the Committee on Asiatic Studies of the American Council on Education, the San Diego American Institute of Pacific Relations Conference and a research trip to Nanking, China; correspondence relating to ACLS Committee on Far Eastern Studies mainly in ACLS files
Box 12
Series XIV. 1949-1951, Back at Cornell; includes material on Nanking trip with unedited copy of diary letters
Boxes 12-13
Series XV. 1951-1955, Miscellaneous correspondence, including David Rowe attack
Boxes 13-14
Series XVI. 1954, Security hearing to appeal denial of security clearance by Eastern Industrial Personnel Security Board for work with Operations Research Office, a research agency for Johns Hopkins University
Box 15
Series XVII. 1954, Security hearing documents
Box 16
Series XVIII. 1955-1957, Cornell Department of History, related material for chairmanship (1956-1964) in that department's files
Box 17
Series XIX. 1957-1960, Miscellaneous correspondence
Boxes 17-18
Series XX. 1960-1963, Miscellaneous correspondence
Boxes 18-19
Series XXI. 1963-1965, Includes 1963 sabbatical trip to Japan, Taiwan, Hong Kong, Indonesia, and Europe
Boxes 19-20
Series XXII. 1965-1968, Includes Wells College Long-Range Planning Committee; correspondence as President of the Association for Asian Studies sent to Association headquarters in Ann Arbor
Boxes 20-21
Series XXIII. 1968-1972, Miscellaneous correspondence up to time of retirement
Boxes 21-22
Series XXIV. 1972-1978, Post-retirement correspondence
Boxes 22-24
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. History Department files
  - A.S.T.P. 1944 (Army Special Training Program) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - I.P.R. Public Relations Material (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - I.P.R. Correspondence 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - I.P.R. Fall 1947 to July 1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - I.P.R. July 1949 to July 1951 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - I.P.R. Mar. 1952 to July 1953 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - I.P.R. Mar. 1952 to July 1953 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - I.P.R. July to Dec. 1951 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - I.P.R. 1953 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - I.P.R. 1954 to 1958 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - I.P.R. 1954 to 1958 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - I.P.R. Final (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Leonard Wilson (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Clifford Maier (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - R. L. Rouse (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Marc Szeftel (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Warren Susman (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence re: Simon Substitute (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Summer School 1957-1961 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Russian History Substitute, Spring 1960 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - National Council on Asian Affairs (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Medieval History Position 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Letters re: T. E. Mommsen (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Theodor E. Mommsen (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Wolfgang Mommsen (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Medieval History Replacement (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - David MacKenzie (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Mario Attilio Levy (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Wolf Laistner (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - M. G. Hutt (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Thomas Helde (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Robert Howes (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - John Hale (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Humanities Council Visitors, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Louis Gottschalk (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Ford Applications for China Program (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Association for Asian Studies - Nomination Committee 1959-1961 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Research Club Membership (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Society of Fellows in the Humanities (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Joint Committee on Contemporary China (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - American Historical Association (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Association for Asian Studies, Regional Meeting Committee (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - American Historical Association, Program Committee (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - American Historical Association, Program Committee (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - American Historical Association, Program Committee (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Inter-university Fellowships in Chinese (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - American Council of Learned Societies (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - American Council of Learned Societies (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - American Council of Learned Societies (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - A.C.L.S. Committees, Apr. to Dec. 1948 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - A.C.L.S. Committee on Far Eastern Studies (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - A.C.L.S. Committee on Far Eastern Studies (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Far Eastern Studies 951 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Far Eastern Studies 951 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Far Eastern Studies 951 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Far Eastern Studies 951-952 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Far Eastern Studies 951-952 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Far Eastern Studies 951-952 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Far Eastern Studies 201 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Far Eastern Studies 201 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Far Eastern Studies 201 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Richard Face (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Robert L. Daniel (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Conference on Asian History (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Arts College Advistory Council (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Ad Hoc Library Committee (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Selig Adler (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Medieval and Renaisance Studies (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Military History - Cooperation with Department of Military Science and Tactics (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - History Teaching Applications 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - History Teaching Applications 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Biggerstaff Memos (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Geoffrey Bruun (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Honors Program 1947-1956 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Departmental, Colleagues, Biographical 1944-1956 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Dean De Kiewiet Departmenal (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Departmental Recommendations 1951 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Departmental - Summer 1950 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Correspondence with Dean - thru Spring Term 1951 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Correspondence with Dean's Office (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Budget 1950 - 1956 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Budget 1936 - 1950 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Correspondence Dean - Arts 1946-1951 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Miscellaneous Pieces
    - Chinese Philosophy - L.C. Porter (Box 3)
    - Seminar on Far Eastern Studies - Hummel, Porter Waren, Iseinda (Box 3)
    - Diplomatic History of the Far East to 1915 - Hornbeck (Box 3)
    - Lecture Notes: History 15, 18 A, B (Box 3)
    - Lecture Notes: History 15 (Box 3)
- Series II. First three years in China (living in Peking), first year at the North China Union Language School learning Chinese, next two years at Yenching University (on a Harvard-Yenching Institute fellowship) pursuing graduate studies in Chinese history; travel in other parts of China, briefly in Korea
  - Chinese Manuscript and Calling Cards 1928-1931. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence (A): Manchurian Trip June 13-July 16, 1929; Shantung Trip January 1931; Shanghai-Shensi Trip May 1930. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence (B): Yangtse Valley Trip April-May 1931; family correspondence 1928-1931. [It appears the correspondence about these trips was a sort of journal kept for documentation of graduate work and study.] (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Chinese Study (C): 1929-1930 documents Biggerstaff's fellowship at Yenching University and University and University of Nanking Institute of Chinese Cultural Studies. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence (C-D): 1928-1931 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence (E-F): 1928-1931 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence (G): 1929, 1930, and n.d. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence (H-J): 1929-1931 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence (K-L): 1928-1931 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence (M): 1928-1930, and n.d. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence (N-O): 1928-1930 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence (R-S): 1928-1931 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence (T-W): 1927-1930 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence (Y-Z): 1928 and n.d. (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Chinese coin - unidentified (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Series III. 1931-1934, Graduate study at Harvard, completing Ph.D.
  - Correspondence (A): 1931-1934 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence (B): 1931-1933 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence (C): 1931-1934 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence (D-F): 1932-1933 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence (H-J): 1931-1933 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence (K-L): 1932-1933 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence (M-O): 1931-1934 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence (P-S): 1932-1934 Penfield Scholarship application, 1933 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence (T-Z): 1931-1933 Biggerstaff's review of The Mind of China by Edwin Harvey. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Manuscripts: 1934 and n.d. includes Chinese lottery ticket, Chinese menu, and program from Harvard Commencement (PhD) (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Series IV. 1934-1936, Post-doctoral study in Peking on Social Science Research Council fellowship. Published An Annotated Bibliography of Selected Chinese Reference Works with S. Y. Teng
  - Correspondence (A): 1936 concerning American Historical Review and American Council of Learned Societies. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence (B): 1933-1936 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence (B): 1934-1936 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence (C-F): 1935-1938 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence (G-J): 1935-1936 includes Chinese manuscript (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence (K-O): 1935-1936 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence (P-R): 1934-1936 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence (S): 1934-1936 includes Social Science Research Council (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence (S): 1933-1936 includes Social Science Research Council (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence (T-V): 1934-1936 includes Chinese manuscript (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence (W-Z): 1935-1936 includes manuscripts: "American Students in China," "The Official Chinese Attitude toward the Burlingame Mission," and notes for speech. (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Japan Trip: 1935 calling cards (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Peking cards: n.d. calling cards (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Series V. 1936-1938, Instructor in Chinese history and language at the University of Washington
  - Memorabilia and manuscript (A): 1933-1935, n.d. includes manuscript "Yenching and its Possibilities". (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence (A-B): 1936-1938 includes program for Fifteenth Session of the Institute of World Affairs, 1937. (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence (C): 1936-1938 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence (D): 1936-1938 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence (E-F): 1936-1938 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence (G): 1936-1938 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence (H-L): 1936-1938 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence (M-O): 1936-1938 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence (P): 1936-1938 includes manuscript "The First Chinese Mission of Investigation Sent to Europe" (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence (P-Q): 1936-1938 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence (R-V): 1936-1938 includes S. Y. Teng (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence (W-Z): 1936-1938 includes resignation from University of Washington. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: 1937 Biggerstaff to wife Camilla (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: 1936 Biggerstaff to wife Camilla (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: 1937, 1938 Camilla to Knight; Clipping: 1929; Lease for apartment in Seattle (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Series VI. 1938-1940, First two years at Cornell as Assistant professor of Chinese History
  - Correspondence: 1938 concerns original appointment as assistant professor of Chinese history (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence (A-B): 1938-1940 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence (C): 1938-1940 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence (C): 1938-1940 includes clippings about development of Far Eastern Studies at Cornell (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence (D-F): 1938-1940 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence (G): 1938-1940 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence (G): 1938-1940 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence (H-J): 1938-1940 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence (K-L): 1938-1940 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence (M-O): 1938-1940 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence (P-Q): 1938-1940 includes death of Dr. Robert T. Pollard (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence (R-S): 1938-1940 includes paper in Chinese (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence (T-V): 1938-1940 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence (W-Z): 1938-1940 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Manuscripts and notes: "Some Notes on the Tung-hua Lu and the Shih-lu" (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Manuscripts and notes: annotated version of "Some Notes on the Tung-hua Lu and the Shih-lu" (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Series VII. 1940-1942, At Cornell, including 1942 Summer Workshop on Far East, British Commonwealth and Latin America and 1941 American Council of Learned Societies Chinese and Japanese Language Courses.
  - University Matters: 1938-1942 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: 1942 concerns 1942 Workshop on Latin America, the Far East, and the British Commonwealth (Box 7, Folder 12-13)
  - Notes: ca. 1936 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Notes: n.d. (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence (A-B): 1940-1942 includes manuscript "Archaeological Researches in China 1923-1924 " (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence (C-D): 1940-1942 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence (E-F): 1940-1942 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence (G): 1940-1942 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence (H-J): 1939-1942 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence (K-M): 1941-1942 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence (N-S): 1940-1942 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence (T-V): 1941-1942 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence (W): 1940-1942 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Manuscripts: 1939, n.d. "The Chinese Joint-Family: Its Role and Recent Trends," "A Reappraisal of the Far Eastern Policy of the United States" (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Manuscripts: 1939-1942 "Anson Burlingame's Instructions from the Chinese Foreign Office," "The 'Right of Rebellion' in China" (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Book Orders 1936-1941 checks, receipts, correspondence and orders (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Series VIII. 1938-1940, Records as Secretary of Committee on Chinese Studies of the American Council of Learned Societies.
  - New York Meeting: 1940 Annual Meeting of the Committee on Chinese and Japanese Studies of the American Council of Learned Societies October 1940 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - ACLS Committee on Chinese Studies report on activities, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, Minutes: 1940 executive committee of American Council of Learned Societies meeting minutes, resumes of applicants for grants (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence 1939-1940 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Y. R. Chao: 1940 correspondence describes Chao's studies, includes manuscript "Proposals for Study of 'General Chinese'" by G. A. Kennedy of Yale (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: 1939 concerns Index to Oriental Art proposed by Helen E. Fernald (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - 1940 Institute describes arrangement for Far Eastern Institute sponsored by Harvard Summer School, Harvard- Yenching Institute and American Council of Learned Societies (Box 8, Folder 18-20)
  - Correspondence regarding Committee on Chinese Studies of the American Council of Learned Societies, February 1937 -September 1939, much concerns fellowship applications. (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence: May-Sept. 1939 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Dec. 1938 -May 1939 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Sept.-Nov. 1938 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: June-Sept. 1938 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Jan.-May 1938 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Dec. 1937 (April 1936, Nov. 1937 ) (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Oct.-Nov. 1937 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Feb.-Sept. 1937 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Series IX. 1940-1941, Records as Secretary of Committee on Chinese Studies of the American Council of Learned Societies
  - Correspondence: 1941 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Annual Committee Meeting: October 1941 reports, minutes, and correspondence (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Conference of Far Eastern Studies: 1940, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: 1941 includes ACLS and Far Eastern Quarterly (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence 1940-1941 committee activities (Box 9, Folder 13-14)
  - Correspondence: 1940-1941 committee activities including ACLS (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - 1941 Language Institute correspondence, announcements, financial records, and reports describe the 1941 Chinese and Japanese Language Institute at Cornell sponsored by ACLS and Cornell Summer Session (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - 1941 Language Institute correspondence, announcements, financial records, and reports describe the 1941 Chinese and Japanese Language Institute at Cornell sponsored by ACLS and Cornell Summer Session (Box 10, Folder 1-4)
- Series X. 1942-1944, War years at Cornell, including material on Committee on Asiatic Studies of ACLS. All material on the Chinese Army Specialized Training Program Biggerstaff directed is filed with other ASTP records in University Archives.
  - Correspondence (A): 1942-1944 includes development of curricula for teaching about Far East for Committee on Asiatic Studies in American Education (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence (A): 1942-1943 Committee on Asiatic Studies in American Education, includes reports (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, reports (A): 1942-1944 Committee on Asiatic Studies in American Education (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Book Reviews (B): 1937-1938, 1940-1943 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence (C): 1942-1944 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence (C): 1939-1944 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence (D-F): 1942-1944 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence (G): 1943-1944 (Box 10, Folder 12)